<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design At Berkeley</title>
    <description>The student-curated website for everything related to design at Berkeley.
</description>
    <link>http://designatberkeley.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://designatberkeley.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:14:06 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 15:14:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Discovered Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During my freshmen year, I went to Calapalooza to find clubs to join. Amongst the sea of tables, fliers, and students, I saw mysterious and overlapping vibrant cyan circles in the corner of eyes. The unique composition of the circular logo piqued my curiosity. So, I walked over to be introduced to &lt;strong&gt;Innovative Design&lt;/strong&gt; (InnoD), a group that makes posters and pretty things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a couple weeks into the semester, I found myself to be really involved with InnoD and I was constantly designing things outside of meetings. I connected with the club really well and one of the older members, Elizabeth, introduced me to a book called &lt;em&gt;The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/em&gt;, which sounded like a lot of what I was doing. So I went and in my search for this book, I found Wurster’s &lt;strong&gt;Environmental Design Library&lt;/strong&gt;, where a trove of books hid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My eyes feasted on the endless rows of books about different design topics, ranging from architecture to industrial and advertisement to social design. I was delighted and my insatiable hunger for design grew. Who knew my confusion and embarrassment from pushing doors that are supposed to be pulled was not actually my fault, but rather the designer’s?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read and I read, I came back to the library day after day, and soon my definition of design had matured from a form of decoration to a manner of construction, a way of creating solutions to problems that I never thought design could fix. From crafting children-friendly MRI experiences to engineering a solar-powered lantern for third-world countries, the possibilities seemed endless. In that moment, as I was sitting on the floor of the library, I thought I had discovered design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next semester, I joined &lt;strong&gt;Berkeley Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;, the only human-centered design club on campus, and worked with people who shared my same understanding of design. It provided me a great space to learn, develop, and collaborate with others on projects. I gained a sense of empathy as I had to understand the motivations and goals behind the people of the things that I were designing for. Surprisingly, psychology seemed to be a big part of design and just as I thought I had a solid grasp of design, I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, design is something that I have stumbled upon and it has become my world. Design isn’t just architecture, engineering, psychology, and business; it’s more than that. It’s a lifestyle and journey that I’ve only recently began and this path only seems to get more exciting. It’ll take time to explore all four corners of design, but hopefully the adventure won’t be lonely. Along the way, I hope to cultivate and help others find and grow their passion for design, so that in the end, we can all discover design together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/16/how-i-discovered-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/16/how-i-discovered-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>get-involved</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;What's your major?&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard this question so many times my Freshman year at Berkeley, and every time, I struggled for an answer. I felt I hadn’t experienced enough of life to firmly know what I wanted to do in the future, and now I realize, I never will. Life is a continuous journey of learning and self-discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first learned about &lt;strong&gt;“design thinking”&lt;/strong&gt; my Freshman year, the things I wanted to do started to make sense. I loved art, music, creativity, and volunteering. The more I learned about design, the more I knew I wanted to use design to create effective, human-centered solutions to social problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored a number of courses and majors during my first two years of college. I considered Business, Biology, Economics, Computer Science, Sustainable Design, or creating my own major in Letters and Science. I joined &lt;strong&gt;Berkeley Innovation&lt;/strong&gt; my sophomore year, where I worked on design projects and met many passionate and creative people. That semester, I also auditioned for AFX, a huge hip hop dance group on campus. Little did I know how that one decision would entirely shift and shape my college experience. Through dance, I grew more confident, more artist, and creative. I learned to use my body as a medium of communication. As a designer, communication is a key component of what you do. You need to communicate to your users, communicate to your client, communicate with your team. The way you present a product is like the way you present a piece of dance choreography: There is a story behind it and you need to learn how to tell that story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decided to major in &lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Science&lt;/strong&gt; to focus on Human-Computer Interaction and learn the emotions behind designing interfaces to connect people and technology. Along the way, I learned the value in taking classes outside of your requirements and in taking classes that expand your perspective. I took classes such as singing, web design decal, guitar decal, stigma and prejudice, landscape architecture, and product design. When creating your schedule, make room for interesting and fun classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one thing you should take from this post, it is to start actively exploring. Attend info sessions for the various &lt;strong&gt;design clubs&lt;/strong&gt; and join one. From there you will meet people who share your passions and can give you multiple perspectives. They will help you and work with you to shape your journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s your first step?”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/15/get-involved-in-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/15/get-involved-in-design/</guid>
        
        
        <category>get-involved</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for Incoming Freshmen from a Freshman</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Take interesting classes. You have four years of college to explore what you want to do and your freshman year is an opportunity to branch out into as many areas as possible. Don’t just take classes for the grade; take classes with interesting professors and topics that interest you. First semester, I didn’t take classes that I was actually interested in. It was frustrating because I knew I had extra time to take more interesting classes and I wasn’t getting the most out of my semester. This semester I decided to take INFO 290, a class where I was surrounded by graduate students and probably had no reason to take. However, I was interested in the topics that were being discussed and I became friends some really cool people. You might not be able to get into upper division or graduate student classes, but if you talk to the professor and show your interest they might let you in or allow you to audit the class. DeCals are also amazing because you can explore some very interesting classes in just about any topic. The &lt;strong&gt;Design DeCal&lt;/strong&gt; provided a great foundation for my introduction into design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might feel overwhelmed the first few months of college and that’s normal. The campus is huge. Make it smaller by joining clubs and organizations. Get involved in as many club meetings/events that you can handle, as early on as possible, during the 1st and 2nd semester so you can figure out which ones are the right fit for you. There are thousands of rooms on campus and its up to you to find a place where you belong. The first time I walked into my first &lt;strong&gt;Design Engineering Collaborative&lt;/strong&gt; (DEC) meeting, in the &lt;strong&gt;Bridges Lounge (the SHED)&lt;/strong&gt; at Bechtel, I felt comfortable hanging out in this space with everyone there. Now I spend most of my free time there with all of my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your top 2-3 choices and commit to them. You CAN be a leader as a freshman in those organizations; make suggestions about events to organize, and volunteer to take responsibility of those events. Contribute to making the organization better and show your dedication. When I joined &lt;strong&gt;Design Council&lt;/strong&gt; in my second semester, someone suggested that we should host a &lt;strong&gt;3D Printing Designathon&lt;/strong&gt;. I volunteered to take charge of the event and brought in people from &lt;strong&gt;3DMC&lt;/strong&gt; and my organization, &lt;strong&gt;DEC&lt;/strong&gt;, to help me put together the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t just stay in your room. You have nothing to lose, put yourself out there. What makes UC Berkeley a great university is the community and not the place. Find cool people, upperclassmen and leaders in the community and ask them for advice, find them on Facebook, and become friends with them. The design community at Berkeley is a relatively close community and once you get to know a few people, you end up knowing everyone else! People are always willing to teach you about design and provide advice for getting more involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/14/tips-for-incoming-freshmen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/14/tips-for-incoming-freshmen/</guid>
        
        
        <category>get-involved</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design by Collaboration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was wandering the rows of tables at Callapalooza during my first semester at Berkeley when the &lt;strong&gt;Design Engineering Collaborative&lt;/strong&gt; caught my eye. They had a massive whiteboard set up with expo markers, sticky notes, and a prompt: “What problem do you want to solve?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I don’t remember what I wrote down, but I was soon attending meetings regularly. We’d come up with “bug lists” from our daily lives and brainstorm solutions as a group. If anyone felt especially passionate about a particular idea, they’d form a team to prototype their solution during the semester. This was not the most elegant nor structured design process, but it got my gears turning on how I could get more involved in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DEC was my first foray into the world of design here at Cal, and I’m now operating as Internal President. Besides leading group projects and teaching students how to solder and 3D print, I’ve also been heavily invested in renovating the &lt;strong&gt;Bridges Lounge&lt;/strong&gt; (also known as the SHED), the room in which DEC and other clubs meet and work. Bridges was once incredibly underutilized, but it’s now developing into a bustling maker space for engineering organizations to work and socialize. I’ve gotten involved with other design groups on campus as well, like the &lt;strong&gt;3D Modeling Club&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April of 2015, DEC and 3DMC collaborated on hosting the university’s first 3D Printing Designathon, a wildly successful event that taught students about 3D design and printing in friendly competition, and spawned corporate relationships with Cal’s design community. That event was largely facilitated by the &lt;strong&gt;Berkeley Student Design Council&lt;/strong&gt;, a group comprising representatives from all of Cal’s design organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s through the Design Council that I’ve met leaders from a multitude of design clubs on campus, representing fields from augmented reality to photography to human-centered design. Design is such a large field that it’s difficult to know where to start, but the Design Council aims to make it more approachable to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/13/design-by-collaboration/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/13/design-by-collaboration/</guid>
        
        
        <category>get-involved</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Design Consulting (Part 2)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In case you didn’t see the first part, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@biancaromulo/spring-break-in-seattle-the-design-edition-6e6ba9ba2d61&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; it is. To recap, I spent my spring break this year touring several design firms around Seattle and I learned a ton about the industry that I wanted to share with you guys. Part 1 recaps the first half of my visit; this is the second. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ziba&quot;&gt;Ziba&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1168/1*2XKRbHEUS1Ds3Rm6im6GBQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ziba's Lobby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ziba’s Lobby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ziba.com/&quot;&gt;Ziba&lt;/a&gt; was the only design firm that I visited in Portland. I had actually found out about Ziba through a friend at UC Berkeley who told me that his family friend (and founder) Sohrab toured his family around the firm when he visited Portland. It turns out that my family friend Christopher, who I was staying with in Seattle, was a co-founder with Sohrab and helped him build it from the ground up, from a garage in Portland to one of the most renowned design firms in the world. He actually designed an IDSA award-winning bathroom squeegee, which you can see in the above picture (it’s the green cylinder object on display on the bottom left hand corner)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*zLYZjYOMb2uyQFi6J6ZTFw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The design library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The design library&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ziba had a presence like no other design firm I’d visited so far had. As I emerged from the staircase from the exit, the lobby with its high ceilings, wood paneling, and beautiful big walls, loomed before me. I was absolutely awstruck. Patty Willert, a recruiter at Ziba, toured me around their spacious office, which included a design library (complete with books &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; every fabric/mateirals you could imagine for their industrial designers) and an auditorium (which unfortunately I could not see as something was going on there at the time). Sam Jeibmann, one of the interaction designers at Ziba, was kind enough to answer some of my questions and below are the insights I gathered from the day trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1200/1*rfvRXsghQ0svb8XtTOfszg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Ziba’s lobby celebrating their 30 year anniversary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ziba’s lobby celebrating their 30 year anniversary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insights&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ziba receives around 500 applications for their internship program annually and take around 2 interns per summer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ziba comprises several branches of design, including branding and marketing, product and packaging, digital design, service design, environment/industrial design, communication design, and business design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 3 fields within the umbrella of interaction design: interaction design (IX), kinetic design (KX), and visual design (VX)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ziba designers believe they are the extension of the client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business design is an emerging field of design in which designers design the trajectory of businesses based on their goals. In addition to research, designers match the businesses’ actionable goals with design strategies. It’s similar to business consulting, but from a design perspective. So while business consulting asks the question “What business goals do we need to achieve?”, business design asks the question “&lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; do we achieve these business goals?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ziba specializes in industrial design (it’s there heritage), B2B projects, consumer projects, and future vision work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building trust with clients is extremely important, and requires transparency and offering what the client asks for while still integrating your own touch into the design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;According to Sam, the design industry has been following a cycle over the last ten years in which aesthetics have shifted from being very real (think skeumorphism) to minimal (think flat design)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of color has increased recently, much like the golden era of 1950s-60s print&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interaction design has shifted to a 2-tier navigational structure (basically a main page + secondary pages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1480/1*2ko4pp9jK2Ih8SU0VXb2jg.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Ziba's building&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ziba’s building&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-for-young-designers&quot;&gt;Tips for Young Designers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have trouble defending your design decisions, always ask “why did I do that” in the design process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design as if you are the client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to people about your design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think of patterns when you design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing is a group process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about conventions (e.g. Apple vs. Android; things become standard for a reason)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The #1 mistake young designers tend to make is that they think they know everything and they’re not open-minded enough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be flexible and malleable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never stop learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tectonic&quot;&gt;Tectonic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*uM-vc1FNKzFIYpY_GaX9VA.png&quot; alt=&quot;The office&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gotectonic.com/&quot;&gt;Tectonic&lt;/a&gt; was vastly different from the last three design firms I visited because of its size. With only 15 designers and located in the heart of Seattle’s hipster district, Capitol Hill, Tectonic was more intimate and family-like. I liked it. A lot. Bill Flora (Principal Creative Director) Mark Gibson (Principal Creative Director), and Nate Landes (Sr. UX Designer) sat down with me and gave me the runthrough of how Tectonic operates. Below are the following insights I gained from my visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insights-1&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic is best known for their motion design and have created beautiful animations for Microsoft, Amazon, Beats, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic also designs consumer tech products ranging from digital platforms and software to shipping products, to physical objects and future vision products such as concept cars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic’s founders led the new redesign of Microsoft&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic likes to think about &lt;strong&gt;what could be&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They also do a little industrial design really well. One of my favorite projects is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bang-olufsen.com/en/sound/sound-systems/beosound-moment&quot;&gt;sound system&lt;/a&gt; they designed for Bang and Olufsen. The wood interface is so sleek and perfectly combines technology with natural material, and on the back there’s a little color wheel that stores songs according to mood. For example, if you’re feeling happy, you can touch the red/orange/yellow part of the color wheel and the sound system will play upbeat music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic is 80% envision and 20% shipping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since there are only 15 designers, they usually work on multiple projects simultaneously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tectonic is very collaborative with their client by establishing clear goals and principles &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*8tntHF44sA1m-fHGjJeGcw.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bill Flora reading a magazine at the office&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bill Flora reading a magazine at the office&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-for-young-designers-1&quot;&gt;Tips for Young Designers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fail fast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design through practice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master flow and use cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tactile&quot;&gt;Tactile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tactileinc.com/&quot;&gt;Tactile&lt;/a&gt; was the last design firm I visited on my trip. Just like Tectonic, Tactile is a very small design firm that was started by Josh Kornfeld, a RISD graduate, around a decade or so ago (back then it was called General Assembly). They are known for working on high-touch products and interactiond design, most notably Microsoft’s XBOX. I sat down with Josh to learn about what goes on in Tactile, and below are the insights I gathered from my visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/fit/c/1600/1600/1*PWvi5VfVsSGVyX88DQf93A.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The sitting area&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The sitting area&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insights-2&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Josh was initially doing freelance work in the early 2000s. Since he was taking on more projects that he had time for, he started hiring other skilled designers to help him with the workload. This turned into General Assembly, which pivoted into Tactile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 17 designers currently at Tactile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each designer works on 2–3 projects at a time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects usually last a few months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each designer has a window view and a giant plant on their desk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tactile likes working on medical technology and tools for professionals that require complex equipment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tactile also likes working on graphic and branding such as XBOX’s special effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each group typically encompasses more than 3 designers with a PM and a design director to give guidance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlike Artefact who like to take young entry-level designers, Tactile prefers working with more senior designers given its small, intimate size&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tactile design process includes investigating what the process of the client company is, conducting research, and refining findings and integrating it into the design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In corporate in-house design teams, designers are more like managers telling design consultancies what to do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To maintain relationships with clients, exceed their expectations, always think of other ways outside of the scope of the assignment in which the product you designed can be used (always provide something extra), think about the big picture, and add extra features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can read more about what Tactile does &lt;a href=&quot;http://tactileinc.com/#/about/top&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-for-young-designers-2&quot;&gt;Tips for Young Designers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a job right out of school to sail ahead of the pack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a healthy process in your portfolio with a concise, brief story of your process. Tell your story eloquently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build your story, conceptualize your solutions, and implement your solutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation skills are super important&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have a design major, that’s okay. Interdisciplinary majors are pretty important in design since they provide a different perspective on things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designers are very visual people therefore they always look at your portfolio to gauge your taste and skills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a unique point of view/personality in your portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your work speaks for itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is cross-posted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@biancaromulo/design-firms-in-seattle-part-2-264dd1f7e55b&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/12/understanding-design-consulting-part-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/12/understanding-design-consulting-part-2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
        <category>physical-product-design</category>
        
        <category>digital-product-design</category>
        
        <category>visual-product-design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Design Consulting (Part 1)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During Spring Break of 2015 I decided to go to the Pacific Northwest to learn about the exciting and unique culture of design consultancy. For those of you who are unfamiliar with design consultancy, I took this definition from IDEO’s “About” page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[Design consultancy] helps organizations in the public and private sectors innovate and grow. We identify new ways to serve and support people by &lt;strong&gt;uncovering latent needs, behaviors, and desires&lt;/strong&gt;. We envision new companies and brands, and we &lt;strong&gt;design the products, services, spaces, and interactive experiences that bring them to life&lt;/strong&gt;. [And] we help organizations &lt;strong&gt;build creative culture and the internal systems required to sustain innovation and launch new ventures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the design consulting industry involves consulting but from a design standpoint. Companies ranging from fledgling startups to Fortune 500 companies come to design consultancies with a problem in a company ranging from rebranding their organization, launching a new product for new types of consumers, or even designing the spaces in which they work. Last year, I became interested in the design industry (which you can read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@biancaromulo/the-beginning-my-gateway-into-design-1ffbe144382a&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and was fascinated about combining business with design to help companies create new products or improve on existing platforms. As it turns out, my godmother’s good friend Christopher helped start &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ziba.com/&quot;&gt;Ziba&lt;/a&gt;, one of the leading design consultancies in the world. Christopher was incredibly kind to me as he invited me to stay at his house and helped me set up private tours with the design firms  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artefactgroup.com/&quot;&gt;Artefact&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teague.com/&quot;&gt;Teague&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ziba.com/&quot;&gt;Ziba&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://gotectonic.com/&quot;&gt;Tectonic&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tactileinc.com/&quot;&gt;Tactile&lt;/a&gt; in the Pacific Northwest. Twenty email correspondences later, I found myself on a plane to Seattle, unsure yet excited about the things I would learn and discover during my trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;artefact&quot;&gt;Artefact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1200/1*FZdD2C_Ch_y22F5dKuxThw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Artefact's Kitchen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artefact’s Kitchen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://artefactgroup.com/&quot;&gt;Artefact&lt;/a&gt;, located in the heart of Pioneer Square, was the first design firm I visited on my trip, so naturally I was very excited as I entered Artefact’s doors. The first thing that I noticed was their kitchen and collaboration space, which was beautiful with their wood floors/ceilings that were nicely juxtaposed with their big windows and steel staircase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*zHtasZlU-peJ6BlH_Y6TAA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Artefact’s Lobby&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artefact’s Lobby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met with Dave Miller, Principle Recruiter of Artefact, who was nice enough to show me around the space and sit down with me to answer some of my questions I had about Artefact and the design industry. Everything that you need to know about Artefact can be found in this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artefactgroup.com/guide/&quot;&gt;cultural guidebook&lt;/a&gt;, but here are some other interesting insights that I gained from this 8 year old design firm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insights&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are no PMs (product managers) at Artefact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designing with the client is extremely important to Artefact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact is a flat organization and you can really create your own job here&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projects typically last from 5 weeks to a whole year, depending on the type of project assigned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact’s design culture is approachable, confident, unconfined, collaborative, self-aware, feedback oriented, and one giant evolving conversation. Real-time, constructive feedback is highly valued, along with no fixed lines and inhibitions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact has this internal incubator called Startefact where designers can create their own projects with other designers. Annually, these designers pitch their ideas to the entire company, and the exec team picks one idea and backs it up with a specified budget&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact’s niche is creating both digital and physical products that are meant for longevity (hence the name “Artefact”). Here, designers like to create applications and products that solve problems and impact society, changing the way people interact with technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact created an internal PM tool called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.10000ft.com/&quot;&gt;10,000 ft&lt;/a&gt; which allows designers to keep track of progress when doing projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-for-potential-interns&quot;&gt;Tips for Potential Interns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact targets young designers who are in their junior/senior year or are entry level fresh graduates with 0–5 years of experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artefact takes one intern per discipline (interaction, visual, industrial design, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicate at a high level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Craft and tell your story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a list of firms you like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick a handful of projects to display on your portfolio that are relevant or share similar characteristics and values with projects that the design firm you’re applying to has. For example, if you’re applying to a design firm known to design really beautiful and functional wearables, have a bunch of wearables projects on your portfolio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about your design process, problem, solution, and outcome in a clear, concise way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defend your design decisions in a rational way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The #1 mistake young designers tend tot make is not networking enough — people care about who took the initiative to reach out first&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Design a business card and give this to people at design events/meetups in your city&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volunteer with community organizations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be open-minded: know where you fit in and what your niche is but don’t close off everything else&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freelance is basically paid networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portfolio-tips&quot;&gt;Portfolio Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recruiters tend to look at the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How you’re talking about your work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether you share similar tastes as the design firm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How polished your portfolio is (a very visual and polished portfolio indicates a high taste bar)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your personality and point of view — shake it up a bit and show some edge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Images are super important&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How you lay out the full design process (problem, process, outcome, what you learned)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relevant coursework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teague&quot;&gt;Teague&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*LrtrV7TZiCjHd5gNwYQAUg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Teague’s front desk with the founder himself&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Teague’s front desk with the founder himself&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, I went downtown to visit Teague, which is apparently one of the oldest design consultancies in the industry (they were founded in 1926). Teague is mostly known for designing airplane interiors, in particular for Boeing Airlines, but they also dabble in designing for tech consumer products. I also noticed that there was a clear sense of legacy as soon as I stepped into their lobby, as they had Walder Dorwin Teague’s face plastered on their wall behind their front desk, as well as an inspiring quote by Teague near the elevator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1200/1*kIJIW4l9v8pQ1xzKlVK3kQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;An inspiring quote from Teague&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An inspiring quote from Teague&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met with Matt McElvogue, Creative Director of Teague, who toured me around the office and chatted with me about Teague:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insights-1&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague values &lt;a href=&quot;http://chiefexecutive.net/ideo-ceo-tim-brown-t-shaped-stars-the-backbone-of-ideoae%E2%84%A2s-collaborative-culture&quot;&gt;T-shaped&lt;/a&gt; people, meaning that you should have a main area of expertise in a particular branch of design, but should have a breadth of knowledge/experience in other facets of design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague likes working on projects that explore the relationship between humans and digital interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague highly values visual impacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are 70 people in Teague’s headquarters, and the rest of the 300 designers do work exclusively for Boeing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague highly values participatory design, meaning that the client is always heavily integrated in the design process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague designs B2B products just like consumer products&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are a user research designer, you travel a lot. It can also be stressful at times, as you are traveling around 3–5 months on average. Work = life sometimes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User researchers have to hire local guides, translators, and recruit agencies to do some external work. They also need to get screeners for the people you interview, and the job requires deep synthesis and observation which they pull into themes and insights they incorporate in their design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designers at Teague are task-based&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meetings usually dictate designers’ work schedules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague uses 10,000 ft, the PM tool that Artefact designed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In terms of cities that are known for design, the San Francisco design industry has more energy, movement, and tiny bundles of opportunity. Seattle’s growth is primarily led by Amazon and Microsoft, but there are a bunch of startups as well. In Munich, designers highly value tradition, and Berlin typically has smaller design firms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/2000/1*qvY1lABzk-RwIqo2A8qdKw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-for-potential-interns-1&quot;&gt;Tips for Potential Interns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recruiters look for fit in terms of style and personality&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teague is currently taking juniors and seniors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead by example&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a passion for learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be willing to fail, and fail fast&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t try to make your designs perfect the first few times around because you’re always going to be iterating anyway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on your soft skills. For example, writing and being able to communicate your decisions are important in design. Be articulate and concise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Portfolio is the #1 most important thing. You don’t need a formal education in design to succeed in the design industry, although it would be helpful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think through making&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make things physical. In other words, always try to create a conceptual model for your designs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just make stuff!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1202/1*V7JEq4OAe8Nauj7iUFPICg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;portfolio-tips-1&quot;&gt;Portfolio Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell stories in the problem, role, issues, process, solution, outcome, reflection order&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice, practice, practice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your pieces need to have a good understanding of form and rendering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;check-out-the-rest-of-my-storyherehttpsmediumcombiancaromulodesign-firms-in-seattle-part-2-264dd1f7e55b&quot;&gt;Check out the rest of my story &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@biancaromulo/design-firms-in-seattle-part-2-264dd1f7e55b&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is cross-posted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@biancaromulo/spring-break-in-seattle-the-design-edition-6e6ba9ba2d61&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/11/understanding-design-consulting-part-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/11/understanding-design-consulting-part-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
        <category>physical-product-design</category>
        
        <category>digital-product-design</category>
        
        <category>visual-product-design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BI Reflection</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking back now on my freshman year, I don’t think I could have been farther from design, at least in terms of what I wanted to do with my life. I arrived to this school as a hopeful premed (yes, really) and my world knew only of biology and chemistry. One and a half years later, I discovered my interest for &lt;strong&gt;computer science&lt;/strong&gt; and an admiration toward the maker community. I had no idea what computer science was or anything, but it was really exciting to see what people did with it. Fast forward two years of struggling, but a lot of learning, I found myself officially declared as a computer science major. That decision—to do computer science and become involved in the engineering community—was the first step in my design career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing computer science exposed me to a lot of amazing groups and individuals. One of the groups was &lt;strong&gt;Berkeley Innovation&lt;/strong&gt;. With BI, I completed my first, portfolio-worthy, design project. Previously, I did a lot of front-end programming, which itself involved a lot of design decisions, but I definitely felt like it all only led up to the work that I’m now doing with BI. One of the first socials that I went to with BI folks was a &lt;strong&gt;design night at Autodesk&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every first Thursday of the month, Autodesk hosts a themed design night that is open to the public at their onsite gallery. I remember feeling so giddy from the thought of going into the city on a weeknight to attend a company-hosted event. Needless to say, I had this child-like grin the whole night. When I got there, the gallery was showcasing a ton of prototypes on design projects that have utilized their software. I was literally a kid in Willy Wonka’s Chocolate Factory. There were hospital building scale models, exoskeleton prototypes, 3D printed cars, cellular transports at the molecular level…the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/bi-reflection1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Collage of exhibits at Autodesk Gallery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/bi-reflection2.png&quot; alt=&quot;BI at Autodesk Design Night group photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being there showed me that design was all around me and it has been that way this whole time. I was so inspired, and I was excited to be so excited. I’ve been back at Autodesk a few times after, and I leave the place thinking, “What have I been doing all my life?” every single time. That’s the kind of career that I want, one that constantly challenges me and pushes my comfort boundaries. That is what design is for me, and hopefully will be for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past four years truly has been a roller coaster ride, and at the end of the day, it was simply my curiosity to learn new things that has led me here. I realize that we all experience things differently, but I encourage you, my reader, to give design a chance. Who knows? It might lead you down your rabbit-hole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/10/bi-reflection/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/10/bi-reflection/</guid>
        
        
        <category>get-involved</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Printing Designathon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On April 4th and 5th at UC Berkeley’s Sutardja Dai Hall, several of Berkeley’s design oriented organizations, including 3D Modeling Club, Design Engineering Collaborative, and Design Council, hosted UC Berkeley’s first ever 3D Printing Designathon. The competition required students to design and 3D print a prototype to improve the life of a UC Berkeley student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With over 70 initial participants, the event started at noon on Saturday and lasted 24 hours. Corporate sponsors for the event included Autodesk, Sculpteo, MadeSolid, and Type A Machines. In addition, Brad Kohlenberg, Business Development Engineer from Made In Space, gave a presentation on 3D Printing and the exciting new frontiers it presents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/3d-printing-designathon-flier.png&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:10px&quot; /&gt;
By 10:00 am the next morning, 14 teams finalized their designs and prepared their presentations for the Designathon showcase. A judging panel, consisting of Carl Bass from Autodesk, Brad Kohlenberg from Made In Space, Ricardo Corona from MadeSolid, Bryan Allen from Type A Machines, and Glenn Katz from Autodesk, attended the showcase and scored each team’s design. Additionally, participants took part in a popular vote to choose their favorite project among their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the showcase, the votes were tallied and the winners were announced. Two teams tied for Judges’ Vote:  team Eggman, with Berni, a customizable attachment that transforms glass bottles into furniture legs and team Nice Guys, with Compact Storage Solutions, a set of Ferris-wheel shelves and a bunk bed desk that maximizes storage in dorm rooms.   Team Fennec Fox, with Lattice Lights, a decorative awning that provides light at night, won the popular vote. The winners from each team received printing credit from Sculpteo and a tour of Autodesk’s Pier 9 Workshop in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UC Berkeley’s design organizations will be hosting another 3D Printing Designathon in the Fall semester, in collaboration with the newly formed Jacobs Institute of Design at UC Berkeley. If you are interested in sponsoring the next Designathon, please contact &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#121;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#105;&amp;#103;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#098;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#121;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#105;&amp;#103;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;winners&quot;&gt;Winners&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;judges-vote&quot;&gt;Judges’ Vote:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eggman - Berni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nice Guys - Compact Storage Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;popular-favorite&quot;&gt;Popular Favorite:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fennec Fox - Light Lattice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;designs&quot;&gt;Designs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various Fried Cephalopods - Cup Holder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shppr  - Built-in external hard drive and battery cellphone case&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oski - Bike Lights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cake N Bake - Volcano Bubbler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WACEC - Computer Suction Lock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rack City - The Kitchen Rack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sensual Engineering Squad - SpaceFunnel9000 Drink Pourer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Golden Bears - Ideal Lecture Hall Seat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CalBand-Pass Filter - Desclip and Desclamp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RAT - GOOB (Get Out Of Bed!) Alarm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Triangle - Triangle Light&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 11:25:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/06/3d-printing-designathon-announcement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://designatberkeley.com/blog/2015/04/06/3d-printing-designathon-announcement/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
        <category>physical-product-design</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
